A Guide to the Papers of Dr. Edward Watson Hook, Jr., 1947-1998
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
The Papers of Dr. Edward Watson Hook, Jr. 1947-1998
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-18
22 linear feet containing 43 boxes: 13 cm x 39.5 cm x 26.5 cm, and 1 artifact box: 46 cm x 39.5 cm x 8 cm. Processed materials total 12,305 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The papers were acquired from the Program of Humanities in Medicine at the University of Virginia School of Medicine.
Biographical/Historical Information
Edward Watson Hook, Jr. was born in Sumter, South Carolina on August 10, 1924. He was the only child of school teacher parents. He obtained a B.S. degree from Wofford College in Spartanburg, South Carolina and then attended Yale University as a participant in the U.S. Army Specialized Training program. He received an M.D. degree from Emory School of Medicine in Atlanta, Georgia in 1949. He served his internship at University Hospital in Minneapolis, Minnesota and was an assistant resident and chief resident in medicine at Grady Memorial Hospital in Atlanta, Georgia. From 1951 to 1953 he served in the U.S. Army Medical Corps. He taught medicine at Emory University and Johns Hopkins University before becoming the Head of the Division of Infectious Disease at Cornell University Medical College in New York in July 1959. In 1966, Hook was a visiting professor at the University of Bahia School of Medicine in Salvador, Brazil. In 1969 he was appointed Henry B. Mulholland Professor of Internal Medicine at the University of Virginia and chaired the department for 21 years. In 1996 Hook was presented with the Thomas Jefferson Award, the highest award given at the University of Virginia. Hook married Jessie Dale Thurecht on June 14, 1949. They had four children, Edward W. III, Susan Dale, Margaret Jane, and Robert Randall. Hook died unexpectedly of a coronary blood clot on October 5, 1998 at the age of 74.
Dr. Hook was involved in a great many organizations and endeavors outside of UVA. He took a leading role in several specialty and subspecialty societies and in organizations concerned with physician education and training. Hook was president of the Infectious Diseases Society of America during 1975-76, was chair of the Board of Scientific Counselors of the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, was a charter member of the editorial board of Antimicrobial Agents and Chemotherapy, and was a chair of the board of directors of the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation Clinical Scholars Program from 1978 to 1988. A former president of the Association of Professors of Medicine, Dr. Hook served on the American Board of Internal Medicine from 1979 to 1987 and chaired its committee on the Evaluation of Clinical Competence.
A fellow of the American College of Physicians (ACP) since 1962 and its president in 1985, Dr. Hook also served as the College’s governor in Virginia and on its board of regents. He visited the People’s Republic of China in 1979 as a member of the ACP’s first teaching delegation to that country. Hook authored over 130 publications. He received distinction early in his career for his research on the pathogenesis of salmonella and other intestinal infections.
Administration duties of running Internal Medicine took up the bulk of Hook's professional time. During his years as chairman, he built up the department of internal medicine, recruited highly trained division leaders, and initiated several programs that benefited the School of Medicine. In 1969 he founded an international health exchange program with the Federal University of Ceará in Brazil. He also developed and led UVa's hospital ethics committee. He began a primary care residency program in medicine and started a faculty-teaching practice program in Orange County. During the 1970s and 80s, Hook was a national leader in internal-medicine manpower, clinical skills evaluation, and the fostering of humanitarian attributes among physicians. Hook was keenly interested in teaching medical students.
After retiring from the chair of the department in 1990, Hook founded the humanities in medicine program. This program offered talks, concerts, and short courses for medical students. He also helped lead the Medical Center Hour, a weekly conference covering health issues. Hook was also chair of the Arts program which used art work to beautify the hospital.
Scope and Content
The Edward Watson Hook materials reflect his wide-ranging professional activities related to heading the Department of Internal Medicine, participating in the larger Health System/University processes, and pursuing his own research and external activities. The documents detail Hook's direct personal participation in professional organizations and also show the wide range of details he coordinated in running the department of internal medicine. A noteworthy aspect of the collection includes an unpublished History of the Department of Medicine written by Byrd Leavell. Hook read and critiqued the manuscript, but Leavell died before completing the book. Also, Hook conducted a series of interviews with Thomas H. Hunter which complement with the Thomas H. Hunter Collection, MS-4, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library.
Arrangement
Series Description: This collection is organized into five principal series, as follows: 1.) Professional Organizations & Activities (9 boxes). 2.) Lectures & Presentations (1 box). 3.) History of UVa Department of Medicine, by Byrd S. Leavell (2 boxes). 4.) Office Files, alphabetically arranged (28 boxes). 5.) Photographs & Artifacts (4 boxes).
Contents List
- SERIES 1: Professional Organizations & Activities
  - Accreditation Council for Graduate Medical Education February 1984-May 1990, [n.d.], 2 TMemo, 11 TLS, 2 ANS, 1 TNS, 2 TD (Box-folder 001-001)
    Re: Hook Service on Panel - UVa accreditation.
  - American Association of Internal Medicine [n.d.], 2 TD's with AN's (Box-folder 001-002)
    Re: Examinations.
  - American Association of University Professors March 7, 1990, 1 TLS (Box-folder 001-003)
  - American Board of Internal Medicine (ABIM) July-October 1969, 2 TMemo, 3 TD, 4 Printed D (Box-folder 001-004)
    Re: Correspondence and related documents; related to Hook's UVa chairmanship.
  - American Board of Internal Medicine (ABIM) January-December 1970, 1 TLS, 1 TN, 3 TMemo (Box-folder 001-005)
    Re: UVa related.
  - American Board of Internal Medicine (ABIM) May 1971-November 1972, 4 TLS, 3 TMemo (Box-folder 001-006)
    Re: UVa related; some documents have Hook's AN's.
  - ABIM January-June 1973; [n.d.], 2 TMemo, 3 TLS, 3 AN, 1 TD (Box-folder 001-007)
  - ABIM January-July 1974, 1 TMemo, 1 TD, 1 TLS (Box-folder 001-008)
    UVa Related.
  - ABIM February 1975-March 1975, 6 TD, 1 TDS, 3 TMemo, 2 TMS (Box-folder 001-009)
    Re: UVa Related.
  - ABIM August-December 1975; 1973, 1 TMemo, 8 TD, 1 brochure, 7 TLS (Box-folder 001-010)
    Re: UVa related; many documents have AN's by Hook.
  - ABIM Summer 1980-July 1981, 4 TLS, 1 TD (Box-folder 001-011)
  - ABIM February-September 1982, 6 TLS, 4 TMemo, 2 TD, 1 Booklet, 1 AN (Box-folder 001-012)
  - ABIM March 1983-December 1986, 1 TLS, 1 AN, 3 TD, 3 TMemo (Box-folder 001-013)
  - ABIM September 1987-April 1990, 4 TLS, 2 TD, 5 TMemo, 1 AN, 2 printed D (Box-folder 001-014)
  - ABIM March-April 1979, 4 TLS, 4 TD (Box-folder 001-015)
    Re: Correspondence and related documents; related to Hook's membership of the Board of Governors. Also, meeting schedules are included.
  - ABIM February-December 1980, 6 TMemo, 1 TLS, 2 TD (Box-folder 001-016)
    Re: Nominations, committee appointments - related to the Board of Governors.
  - ABIM January-May 1981, 3 TLS, 2 TMemo, 1 TDS, 2 TD (Box-folder 001-017)
    Re: Board of Governors related.
  - ABIM June-August 1981, 5 TLS, 1 TMemo, 4 TD (Box-folder 001-018)
  - ABIM September-December 1981, 3 TMemo, 4 TLS, 2 TD (Box-folder 001-019)
  - ABIM January 1982, 2 TMemo, 8 TLS, 1 TD, 1 AN (Box-folder 001-020)
    Re: Board of Governors related; misc., including clinical judgment pretest content.
  - ABIM February-April 1982, 6 TLS, 1 TD, 1 TMemo (Box-folder 001-021)
  - ABIM July-August 1982, 10 TMemo, 5 TLS, 1 TD (Box-folder 001-022)
  - ABIM September-December 1982, 8 TLS, 1 TMemo, 2 TD, 1 AN (Box-folder 001-023)
    Re: Board of Governors related; misc., including evaluation of procedural skills of residents.
  - ABIM January-May 1983, 1 TMemo, 1 TD, 2 TLS (Box-folder 001-024)
    Re: Board of Governors related, misc, including evaluating procedural skills of residents.
  - ABIM July-November 1983, 1 TMemo, 4 TLS, 1 TD, 1 TDS (Box-folder 001-025)
    Re: Board of Governors related; committee appointments.
  - ABIM January-March 1984, 2 TMemo, 3 TD, 5 TLS (Box-folder 001-026)
    Re: Board of Governors related; misc., including membership nominations, PMP evaluations.
  - ABIM May-November 1984, 3 TMemo, 6 TLS, 3 TD (Box-folder 001-027)
    Re: Board of Governors related, misc, including certification standards, rating humanistic qualities.
  - ABIM January-July 1985, 1 TMemo, 1 TD, 5 TLS (Box-folder 001-028)
  - ABIM June-December 1986, 5 TLS (Box-folder 001-029)
  - ABIM September 1987-June 1988, 5 TLS, 2 TMemo (Box-folder 001-30)
  - ABIM January 1989-May 1990; January [n.d.], 4 TLS, 1 TMemo, 3 TD, 1 journal article reprint (cover page), 1 AN w/envelope (Box-folder 002-001)
    Re: Board of Governors.
  - ABIM November 1978-February 1981, 1 TLS, 1 TMemo, 3 booklets, 2 TD, 1 journal article (Box-folder 002-002)
    Re: Committees: CECC (Committee to Evaluate Clinical Competence).
  - ABIM May 1981, 4 TLS, 3 TD, 1 printed D, 1 TD w/ AN's (Box-folder 002-003)
    Re: Committees: CECC & Subcommittee to Standardize Programs of Evaluation of Clinical Competence at the Local Level (SSPECCLL).
  - ABIM June-July 1981, 1 TLS, 3 TM, 1 journal article (first page only), 1 AN, 1 TD (Box-folder 002-004)
    Re: Committees; CECC and SSPECCLL.
  - ABIM September-December 1981, 3 TLS, 1 TD (Box-folder 002-005)
  - ABIM January-May 1982, 2 TLS, 4 TD, 1 TM (Box-folder 002-006)
  - ABIM May 1982, Collected TD's to form agenda book (Box-folder 002-007)
    Re: Committees; CECC and Subcommittee to Review Special Evaluations.
  - ABIM June-December 1982, 4 TLS, 1 TLS (draft), 2 TM, 2 TD (Box-folder 002-008)
  - ABIM March-June 1983, 6 TD, 2 AN, 1 TM (Box-folder 002-009)
  - ABIM August 1983; 1987, 5 TLS, 1 journal article, 2 TM, 2 TD (Box-folder 002-010)
    Re: Committees: CECC, SSPECLL, misc, including history of CECC, 1970-1987.
  - ABIM December 1989-March 1990, 1 TM, 1 set of TDs, printed Ds making up agenda set (Box-folder 002-011)
    Re: Committees; CECC - Advisory committee to CECC (includes Clinical competence and Hospital visit programs, history of CECC and Hook's involvement).
  - ABIM 1987; [n.d.], 1 TM, 1 TD, 2 AN (Box-folder 002-012)
    Re: Committees; subcommittee on hospital visit program (part of CECC), includes Hook's AN's on program.
  - ABIM March 1978-February 1980, 3 TLS, 1 TD, 1 T/AD (Box-folder 002-013)
    Re: Hospital Evaluation visits, including Hook's report on Louisiana State University Medical Center visit.
  - ABIM October 1980-March 1984, 3 TLS, 2 TDS, 2 AN (Box-folder 002-014)
    Re: Hospital Evaluation Visits, including Hook's evaluation of Ochsner Medical Foundation, New Orleans.
  - ABIM September 1986, 1 TDS (Box-folder 002-015)
    Re: Hospital Evaluation Visits, Hook's evaluation of University of South Florida affiliated Hospitals.
  - ABIM November 19, 1986, 1 TLS, 1 TDS (Box-folder 002-016)
    Re: Hospital Evaluation Visits, Hook's evaluation of St. Elizabeth's Hospital, Elizabeth, NJ.
  - ABIM November 21, 1986, 1 TLS, 1 TDS (Box-folder 002-017)
    Re: Hospital Evaluation Visits, Hook's evaluation of University of Miami/Jackson Memorial Medical Center.
  - ABIM December 1986, 2 TLS, 1 TDS (Box-folder 002-018)
    Re: Hospital Evaluation Visits, Hook's evaluation of Orlando Regional Medical Center, Florida.
  - ABIM April 1989-October 1990, 4 TLS, 3 TD (Box-folder 002-019)
    Re: Hospital Evaluation Visits, Hook's evaluation of Providence Hospital, Washington D.C.
  - ABIM October-November 1990, 3 TLS, 2 TD (Box-folder 002-020)
    Re: Hospital Evaluation Visits, Hook's evaluation of Atlantic City Medical Center, N.J.
  - ABIM August-November 1990, 3 TLS, 2 TD (Box-folder 003-001)
    Re: Hospital Evaluation Visits; Hook's evaluation of Jersey City Medical Center.
  - ABIM July-November 1990, 3 TLS, 1 TD, 1 AN (Box-folder 003-002)
    Re: Hospital Evaluation Visits; Hook's evaluation of Booth Memorial Medical Centery, Flushing, N. Y.
  - ABIM 1977-1982, Collected TD's to form set on subcommittee's process (Box-folder 003-003)
    Re:Committees; Subcommittee to Review Special Evaluations (part of Committee to Evaluate Clinical Competence).
  - ABIM April-June 1981, 1 AN, 2 journal articles, 5 TD, 1 TMemo, 1 TLS, 2 ALS (Box-folder 003-004)
    Re: Committees; Subcommitte on Humanism (part of committee to evaluate clinical competence - CECC) - Hook served on subcommittee and includes preliminary material to forming subcom.
  - ABIM July-November 1981, 4 TLS, 8 journal articles (1st pages only), 1 TMemo, 4 TD, 1 pamphlet (Box-folder 003-005)
    Re: Committees; Subcommittees on Humanism including planning formation of subcommittees, many AN's on documents.
  - ABIM January-February 1982, 3 TMemo, 9 TD, 4 AN, 1 TLS, 6 T/AD, 3 journal articles (copies) (Box-folder 003-006)
    Re: Committees; Subcommittee on Humanism.
  - ABIM February-March 1982, 1 TLS, 5 T/AD, 10 T/ADS (Box-folder 003-007)
    Re: Committees; Subcommittee on Humanism (planning formation of subcommittee).
  - ABIM May-June 1982, 2 TMemo, 3 TD, 2 Journal/book article copies, 1 AN, 1 TMs, 1 TLS (Box-folder 003-008)
    Re: Committees; Subcommittee on Humanism (subcommittee meeting).
  - ABIM June-November 1982, 1 TM, 5 TD, 1 AN (Box-folder 003-009)
    Re: Committees: Subcommittee on Humanism (subcommittee meeting).
  - ABIM November 1982-January 1983, 1 TMemo, 5 TD, 2 TLS, 1 news clipping, 1 journal article, 1 booklet (Box-folder 003-010)
  - ABIM January-October 1983, 9 TLS, 4 TD, 2 journal article, 1 ANS, 1 booklet (Box-folder 003-011)
    Re: Committees; Subcommittee on Humanism (April meeting).
  - ABIM June-October 1983, 14 TLS, 2 journal articles, 7 TD, 3 TMemo, 1 ANS, 2 ALS (Box-folder 003-012)
    Re: Committees; Subcommittee on Humanism (October meeting).
  - ABIM January-February 1984, 4 TLS, 2 ANS, 1 pamphlet, 1 TMs (Box-folder 003-013)
  - ABIM March-April 1984, 2 TMemo, 3 TLS, 1 TMs, 1 TD, 3 journal article copy (Box-folder 003-014)
  - ABIM May-August 1984, 1 TLS, 1 TMs (Box-folder 003-015)
    Re: Committees; Subcommittee on Humanism (MS describes experiences of a UVa patient).
  - ABIM February-April 1985, 1 ANS, 1 TMs, 1 journal article, 1 TMemo (Box-folder 003-016)
    Re: Committees; Subcommittee on Humanism (1985 Guide to Humanistic Qualities in the Internist, Hook in one of the authors).
  - ABIM March-June 1985, 1 TL, 2 T/A MS, 1 printed booklet, 1 newsletter (Box-folder 003-017)
  - ABIM June 1985, 1 TMemo, 1 TD, 1 envelope, 2 printed booklets (Box-folder 003-018)
    Re: Committees; Subcommittee on Humanism (Humanism Guide).
  - ABIM May-August 1980, 2 TLS, 1 TMemo, 1 AMemo, 5 TD, 3 TMs (Box-folder 004-001)
    Re: Conferences (Hook presentation on geriatrics).
  - ABIM July-December 1981, 1 TLS, 1 TMs, 2 TMemo, 2 ANS, 2 TD (Box-folder 004-002)
    Re: Conferences (Hook presentation on evaluation of humanism).
  - ABIM July-August 1987, 3 TLS, 1 TMemo, 1 TMs (Box-folder 004-003)
    Re: Conferences (Hook comments on task force report).
  - ABIM 1979-1980, 2 Booklets (Box-folder 004-004)
    Re: Report on Clinical Competence, Report on Committee on Standards of Excellence.
  - ABIM: Publications 1981-1984, 4 Booklets (Box-folder 004-005)
    Re: Reports: Evaluation of Clinical Competence.
  - ABIM: Publications 1986-1987, 2 booklets, 2 pamphlets, 1 TMemo, 1 folder (Box-folder 004-006)
    Re: Policies & Procedures, Evaluation of Clinical Competence, Evaluation of Residents.
  - American Board of Medical Specialties April-December 1981, 3 TLS, 4 TD, TMs (Box-folder 004-007)
    Re: Hook's presentation on evaluation of noncognitive skills and clinical performance.
  - American Clinical & Climatological Association October 1965-November 1990, 2 TD, 15 TLS, 1 TMemo, 1 program, 1 ANS, 1 TMs (Box-folder 004-008)
    Re: Hook's election, participation in specific events.
  - American College of Physicians January 1971-December 1973, 6 TLS, 2 printed programs, 2 TD (Box-folder 004-009)
    Re: ACP course "Recent Advances in Infectious Diseases" at UVa.
  - American College of Physicians February 1977-April 1978, 22 TLS, 5 TD, 2 TMemo, 2 T/AD (Box-folder 004-010)
    Re: ACP chapter in Virginia (regional meeting planning & program, course "Current Concepts of Clinical Infectious Disease").
  - American College of Physicians September 1981-December 1984, 19 TLS, 1 TMs, 1 ALS, 1 TMemo, 1 publication, 2 TD (Box-folder 004-011)
    Re: By-laws revision regarding UVa ACP membership, statement on in-patient respiratory care, programming, Hook's election as President, financing graduate medical education, practice abroad programs, relocation of ACP headquarters, report of Task Force on College Structure and Function, long-range planning.
  - American College of Physicians January-April 1985, 40 TLS, 3 TD, 1 TMs (Box-folder 004-012)
    Re: Hook's presidency, headquarters move, conference planning, meeting planning, ACP executive vice president search, graduate medical education.
  - American College of Physicians May-July 1985, 24 TLS, 2 TD, 1 booklet (Box-folder 004-0013)
    Re: Hook's presidency, conference & meeting planning, funding graduate medical education, executive vice president search, primary care physicians within ACP.
  - American College of Physicians August-November 1985, 34 TLS, 2 TD, 1 journal article copy (Box-folder 005-001)
    Re: Hook's presidency, meeting planning, executive vice president search, funding of graduate medical education, Hook Senate testimony, Canadian ACP membership.
  - American College of Physicians December 1985-March 1987, TLS, TD, 1 booklet, ALS, ANS (Box-folder 005-002 [NAPNAP])
    Re: Hook's presidency (and later), ACP delineation of responsibilities, support for general internal medicine and its protection by ACP, executive vice president search, medical infomatics, relations with other medical associations, conference planning, graduate medical education funding, ACP scholarships, translation of MKSAP into Japanese, Supreme Court decision on ACP tax question.
  - American Federation for Clinical Research May 1983-August 1989, 19 TLS, 1 ANS, 3 TD, 3 TMemo, 1 brochure (Box-folder 005-003)
    RE: Misc; nominations of Veldhuis for award.
  - American Geriatric Society July 1985-March 1988, 6 TLS, 2 TD (Box-folder 005-004)
    Re: Membership fellowships.
  - American Medical Association February 1970-August 1990, 16 TLS, 1 TD, 3 TMs (Box-folder 005-005)
    Re: Medical faculty as clinicians, family practice residencies & clerkships, radon.
  - American Society for Clinical Investigation May 1982-August 1986, 1 TLS, 2 TMemo (Box-folder 005-006)
    Re: Meeting, young clinical investigator award.
  - American Society for Microbiology January 1965-July 1980, 17 TLS, 1 TD, 1 ALS (Box-folder 005-007)
    Re: Editorial Board of journal "Animicrobial Agents & Chemotherapy", "Journal of Clinical Microbiology" controversy, memberships.
  - American Society for Microbiology August 1980-February 1981, 12 TLS, 4 TD, 3 TMemo (Box-folder 005-008)
    Re: Membership, journals; editorial work, content.
  - American Society of Internal Medicine March 1981-December 1985, 5 TLS, 1 journal article, 1 TD (Box-folder 005-009)
    Re: Relations between ASIM and American College of Physicians.
  - Association of American Medical Colleges 1976-June 1989, 10 TLS, 8 TD, 1 journal article copy, 1 ANS, 6 TMemo, 2 AN, 3 TMs (Box-folder 005-010)
    Re: Miscellaneous; AAMC agreement with Association of Professors of Medicine, houses staff remuneration, faculty practice survey, women in medicine program, work group on withholding physician's services, executive development seminar.
  - Association of American Physicians April 1971-November 1990, 18 TLS, 1 TD (Box-folder 005-011)
    Re: Miscellaneous, mostly support of nominations for membership.
  - Association of American Physicians August 1977-March 1989, 40 TLS, 1 TMemo (Box-folder 005-012)
    Re: UVa faculty nominations.
  - Association of Professors of Medicine May 1971-December 1978, 10 TLS, 1 TD, 1 ALS, 7 TMemo, 1 news article copy (Box-folder 005-013)
    Re: Legislation affecting physicians; relations with other organizations; misc. business (Hook served on APM council 1977-1980; APM president 1981-82).
  - Association of Professors of Medicine February 1979-September 1980, 9 TLS, 4 TD, 5 TMemo, 1 T/A Memo, 2 journal articles (Box-folder 005-014)
    Re: Legistaion, meetings, council meeting items.
  - Association of Professors of Medicine January-June 1981, 14 TLS, 1 TD, 2 TMemo, 1 TMs (Box-folder 005-015)
    Re: Legislation, meetings, issues affecting internal medicine - Hook's presidency of APM.
  - Association of Professors of Medicine July-December 1981, 20 TLS, 20 TD, 1 TMs, 2 TMemo, 1 pamphlet (Box-folder 006-001)
    Re: Legislation, issues affecting internal medicine, graduate medical education meetings - Hook's presidency of APM.
  - Association of Professors of Medicine January-March 1983, 14 TLS, 1 TD, 3 TMemo (Box-folder 006-002)
    Re: Legislation, issues affecting internal medicine, meetings - Hook's presidency of APM.
  - Association of Professors of Medicine March 24-October 1982, 25 TLS, 1 TMemo, 2 TMs, 1 brochure, 1 journal article (Box-folder 006-003)
  - Association of Professors of Medicine July 1983-April 1990, 13 TLS, 1 AN, 3 TD, 2 TMemo, 1 TMs (Box-folder 006-004)
    Re: Legislation, issues affecting internal medicine, graduate medical eduction, APM functions and budget.
  - Association of Professors of Medicine May-June 1981, 30 TLS (Box-folder 006-005)
    Re: Legislative issues - correspondence to and from congress members.
  - Association of Professors of Medicine July 1981-August 1983, 9 TLS, 2 TMs, 1 TMemo (Box-folder 006-006)
    Re: Correspondence with legislators; Hook's Senate testimony on research funding.
  - Association of Professors of Medicine 1975-1986, 8 TLS, 3 TD, 1 TMs, 5 TMemo (Box-folder 006-007)
    Re: APM Task Force on Manpower Needs (Hook was a member).
  - Association of Professors of Medicine 1983-1987, 2 TLS, 4 TD (Box-folder 006-008)
    Re: UVa departmental profile - UVa questionnaire results on internal medicine training program.
  - Association of Program Directors in Internal Medicine 1981-1988, 3 TMemo, 1 TMs, 6 TLS, 6 TD, 1 Program (Box-folder 006-009)
    Re: Misc. issues relating to residency training, certification standards, meetings, membership.
  - Board of Scientific Counselors, National Institute of Allergy & Infectious Diseases June 1973-May 1979, 8 TLS, 4 TD, 1 TMemo (Box-folder 006-010)
    Re: Hook's participation on Board grant appraisals.
  - Infectious Diseases Society of America 1963-September 1975, 32 TLS, 2 TD, 2 TMemo (Box-folder 006-011)
    Re: Hook presidency, relations with other associations, programming, guidelines for antimicrobial therapy.
  - Infectious Diseases Society of America October-December 1975, 30 TLS, 1 TMemo, 3 TD (Box-folder 006-012)
    Re: Hook presidency; guidelines for antimicrobial therapy, guidelines for training in infectious diseases, accreditation of conference by AMA.